Finding Aid for Field Family papers, 1836-1940
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Field Family papers 1836-1940
Field Family.
2 linear feet
851213 Aa 2
Residents of Englishville and Grand Rapids, Michigan; family papers.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mrs. Roy Holmes (donor no. 844 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Fields family members were residents of Englishville and Grand Rapids, Michigan.
The collection is comprise of two series: Correspondence and Other family papers. Included is business and family correspondence of Abby Field, a worker with the Church of Christ of Englishville and Grand Rapids, Michigan. There is also correspondence of Myron and Susan Field Buck, Sylvester Field and Flora Bennett. Beyond correspondence, the collection includes a scattering of newspaper clippings, legal papers, diaries, and other materials relating to personal affairs, farm life and the Civil War.
Subjects:
Buck family.; Church of Christ (Englishville, Mich.); Englishville (Mich.); Farm life--Michigan--Kent County.; Farmers--Michigan--Kent County.; Grand Rapids (Mich.); Women--Religious life--Michigan--Kent County.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Women--Religious life--Michigan--Kent County.; Women--Michigan--Kent County.
Contributors:
Bennett, Flora.; Buck, Myron.; Buck, Susan Field.; Field, Abby, 1844-1901.; Field, Sylvester.
Genre Terms:
Diaries
- Correspondence
  - 1848 and 1852-1896, 38 folders (Box 1)
  - 1897-1922, 16 folders (Box 2)
- Other family papers
  - Genealogical charts by Myrtle Field Holmes, ca. 1940 (Box 2)
  - Clippings, 1870-1940 (Box 2)
  - Deeds, Bills, Indentures, etc., 1836-1889 (Box 2)
  - Diaries and Sunday School rolls kept by Abby Field, ca. 1875 (Box 2)
  - Papers and essays by Abby Field, Myrtle Field Holmes and others, undated (Box 2)
  - Penmanship, book of Sylvester Field, 1878 (Box 2)
  - Notebook of Sylvester Field, 1889 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous books and notebooks, 1884 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets, handbills, etc., undated (Box 2)